a good health insurance policy helps as
it reimburses your hospital costs and
doesn't strain your finances
but buying health insurance is difficult
there are premiums product features and
claims track record to understand
that's where money control secure now
health insurance ratings comes in
a brand new tool from money control that
helps you pick the best health insurance
policy
so where to begin
log on to www.moneycontrol.com
go to the money control secure now
health insurance ratings page here
you will find ratings of more than 130
health insurance policies across 27
insurance companies
policies that are not only comprehensive
but also have a good track record as far
as the claims experience goes
before you go looking for health
insurance you might want to spend some
time reading up on the money control
secure now health insurance ratings the
methodology the different parameters on
which we painstakingly rated all the
policies and finally the most important
of them all how to use the money control
secure now health insurance ratings
[Music]
oh and we've made some cool videos that
give you a good idea too about our
ratings
now let's spend some time in getting you
that perfect health insurance plan
enter the age closest to you
who you want to buy the policy for
whether it's just for you or for your
entire family
a family floater plan as we call it
and how much cover do you need
a few things to remember here for age we
have chosen four broad age brackets
ages 30 45 60 and 75
since these are the main age landmarks
in a person's life cycle we decided to
rate policies based on premiums for each
of these age brackets
one person's some short requirement can
be vastly different from another's
to reach a common ground for rating
health insurance policies and be as
comprehensive as possible we decided to
rate policies on four different some
assured amounts
money control secure now health
insurance ratings rates health insurance
policies based on four different sum
assured amounts
5 lakh 10 lakh 20 lakh and 50 lakh
hit submit and you get your complete
list of health insurance plans suited
for you
all our policies get three types of
ratings
a
b and c
a rated policies are the highest
c rated ones the lowest here you'll be
able to see how many policies have got a
a b or c rating
start with the a rated policies
these are policies that score at least
65 marks
typically these are policies that will
have most of the essential features that
we have identified
we've sorted them by the score
next to a policy score you'll see the
premium for that age group
waiting period for pre-existing disease
whether or not it has a cap on groom
rent
its claim settlement ratio and the link
to see more of that plan
you can select any a rated policy with
either the lowest premium or the highest
score or any other key parameter that
we've listed out for you on the home
page
and then click on plan details at the
extreme right
here get to know your chosen health
insurance plans a bit more we've listed
out several other key features of your
policy
take a few minutes to study your policy
a bit more for each of the policies get
to know the claim settlement rate claim
complaints per 10 000 claims
and claims aging percentage of claims
settled within one month
this should give you an idea of how
responsive your health insurance policy
really is
of all the three customer service
parameters money control secure now
health insurance ratings gives the
highest points to percentage of claims
settled
we hope you find money control secure
now health insurance ratings useful
do write in to us with your feedback we
look forward to hearing from you
[Music]